Guide to the Hallie Flanagan Papers, circa 1890-1988
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES II. WRITINGS, 1904-1953
  - Writings of HFD: Travel notes/diaries
    - Europe, 1926 Aug - 1927 May; (MS diary) (Folder 18.144)
    - Moscow [feature Gordon Craig and Stanislavsky], 1926 Oct-Nov; (MS diaries I-III) (Folder 18.145)
    - Leningrad; Berlin [feature Dr. Horsley Gantt], 1926 Dec; (MS diaries) (Folder 18.146)
    - Europe, 1926 Sep - 1927 Jan; (MS notebook) (Folder 19.147)
    - Europe, 1927 Feb-May; (MS notebook) (Folder 19.148)
    - Europe, 1926 Jul-Sep; (TS transcripts- excerpts from MS diary) (Folder 19.149)
    - Europe, 1927 Mar-Apr; (TS transcripts- excerpts from MS diary) (Folder 19.150)
    - Europe, 1926-1927; (TS transcripts- excerpts from MS notebook (Folder 19.151)
    - Russia; Turkey, 1930; (MS notebook) (Folder 19.152)
    - Turkey, train trip north, 1930; (MS diary) (Folder 19.153)
    - Europe, 1930 May-Jun; (TS transcripts - excerpts from MS notebook) (Folder 19.154)
    - Europe, 1934 Mar-Aug; (MS diary) (Folder 20.155)
    - Europe, 1934 Feb-Apr; (MS notebook) (Folder 20.156)
    - Europe, 1934 May-Jun; (MS notebook) (Folder 20.157)
    - Europe, 1934 Jul-Aug; (photocopies of MS notebook) (Folder 20.158)
    - Europe, 1934 Feb-May; (transcripts - excerpts from MS diary) (Folder 20.159)
  - Writings of HFD: Notebooks
    - New York theater season, 1925-1926; (MS notebook) (Folder 20.160)
    - Miscellaneous, 1926-1927; (MS notebooks) (Folder 20.161)
    - Federal Theatre Project, 1936-1938; (TS notebooks) (Folder 20.162)
  - Writings of HFD: Dramatic works
    - The Curtain, 1922; (published) (Folder 20.163)
    - The Garden of Wishes, 1923; (TS carbon) (Folder 20.164)
    - The Garden of Wishes, 1923; (TS carbon) (Folder 20.165)
    - Incense [written ca. 1923-1924], 1925; (TS carbon) (Folder 21.166)
    - Incense [written ca. 1923-1924], 1925; (TS carbon w/ penciled editing) (Folder 21.167)
    - Incense [written ca. 1923-1924], 1925; (photocopy of TS w/ director's comments - original in Yale School of Drama library) (Folder 21.168)
    - Incense [written ca. 1923-1924], 1925; (mimeograph of TS - later note by HFD on title page ?) (Folder 21.169)
    - Free [written summer 1924], (photocopy of TS) (Folder 21.170)
    - Here Comes the Bridegroom - Grinnell years, undated; (TS) (Folder 21.171)
    - Here Comes the Bridegroom - Grinnell years, undated; (TS carbon) (Folder 21.172)
    - Can You Hear Their Voices, by HFD and Margaret Ellen Clifford, 1931; (published) (Folder 22.173)
    - Fear - Acting version by HFD, 1933; (TS carbon) (Folder 22.174)
    - The Sky Will Be Lit Up, by HFD and Janet Hartman, 1933; (photocopy of TS - original at Library of Congress) (Folder 22.175)
    - The Lost Aphrodite: [a Comedy on Archaeology], 1934; (work copy - part TS, part TS carbon) (Folder 22.176)
    - Chorus for the Delian Apollo, circa 1934; (published, 2c.) (Folder 22.177)
    - Margaret Fuller, by HFD and Nathalie Wolfe, circa 1939; (TS) (Folder 22.178)
    - Margaret Fuller, circa 1939; (TS carbon) (Folder 23.179)
    - No Time for Tears, 1940 or 1944?; (TS) (Folder 23.180)
    - E = mc2: a Living Newspaper About the Atomic Age, 1947; (published - autographed by HFD for Joanne Davis Bentley) (Folder 23.181)
    - Heritage: a Play in Honor of the 75th Anniversary of the Founding of Smith College, 1953; (published - autographed by HFD for Eric Bentley) (Folder 23.182)
    - Trust Emily, undated; (TS carbon) (Folder 23.183)
    - Introduction for unidentified play or series of scenes, undated; (TS carbon) (Folder 23.184)
  - Writings of HFD: Essays / articles
    - Essays/articles, 1924-1927; (7 items, published) (Folder 24.185)
    - Essays/articles, 1927-1929; (2 items, TS carbons) (Folder 24.186)
    - Essays/articles, 1931-1939; (12 items, TS, TS carbons) (Folder 24.187)
    - Essays/articles, 1929-1930; (5 items, published) (Folder 24.188)
    - Essays/articles, 1931-1932; (2 items, published) (Folder 24.189)
    - Essays/articles, 1934; (4 items, published) (Folder 24.190)
    - Essays/articles, 1936; (1 item, published) (Folder 24.191)
    - Essays/articles, 1937; (3 items, published) (Folder 25.192)
    - Essays/articles, 1938; (1 item, TS) (Folder 25.193)
    - Essays/articles, 1939-1940; (6 items, published) (Folder 25.194)
    - Essays/articles, [1947?]; (1 item, TS) (Folder 25.195)
    - Essays/articles, 1947; (1 item, published) (Folder 25.196)
    - Essays/articles, 1952; (1 item, published) (Folder 25.197)
    - Essays/articles, undated; (4 items, TS, TS carbons) (Folder 25.198)
  - Writings of HFD: Poetry and Fiction
    - Undergraduate poetry: photocopies from 1911 Grinnell Annual, (10 pages) (Folder 25.199)
    - Fiction: photocopies from Unit, Grinnell's literary magazine, 1908-1910; (6 items) (Folder 25.200)
    - Fiction: The Ant and the Statue, 1925-1935; (19 pages, incomplete, TS carbon) (Folder 25.201)
    - Fiction: In His Image, [1925-1935?]; (TS carbon) (Folder 25.202)
    - Fiction: In His Image, [1925-1935?]; (TS carbon w/ penciled editing) (Folder 25.203)
    - Fiction: Maps of the Moon, [1925-1935?]; (TS carbon, 2 copies) (Folder 25.204)
    - Fiction: Pearls Found in a Bottle, [1925-1935?]; (TS carbon with penciled editing) (Folder 25.205)
    - Fiction: Miscellaneous, 1925-1935; (TS and TS carbons, 3 items) (Folder 25.206)
    - Fiction: Miscellaneous Smith years, undated; (TS and TS carbons, 5 items) (Folder 25.207)
  - Writings of HFD: Speeches
    - Federal Theatre Project, 1935 Oct - 1937 May; (TS notebooks, 4 items) (Folder 26.208)
    - Federal Theatre Project, 1937; (TS notebooks, 4 items) (Folder 26.209)
    - Federal Theatre Project, 1938; (TS notebooks, 5 items) (Folder 26.210)
    - Federal Theatre Project: "A Brief Delivered by HFD... before the Committee on Parents,", 1938 Feb 8; (TS mimeograph, 2 copies) (Folder 26.211)
    - Federal Theatre Project: speech at National Theatre Conference, 1940; (Published; photocopy) (Folder 26.212)
    - Vassar: Chapel Talk to class of 1941, 1941 May 21; (Published) (Folder 26.213)
    - Smith College: assembly talks, 1942 Sep - 1944 Jan; (photocopy of TS) (Folder 26.214)
    - Smith College: The Drums of Taos, 1944 Jan 26; (photocopy of TS, 2 copies) (Folder 26.215)
    - Shifting Scenes stereotype plates, 1928; (32 boxes) (Boxes 60-91)
  - Writings of others
    - [William H. Bridge?]: essay on Ruth St. Denis and the Society of Spiritual Art, undated (Folder 27.216)
    - Whittaker Chambers: Can You Make Out Their Voices, 1931; (published; photocopy) (Folder 27.217)
    - Kate Clugston: excerpts from her autobiography, re: HFD and Federal Theatre Project, undated; (photocopy of TS) (Folder 27.218)
    - Kate Clugston: Very Like a Whale [excerpts], undated; (photocopy of TS) (Folder 27.219)
    - Philip Davis: non-fiction/articles, 1934-1937; (published) (Folder 27.220)
    - Philip Davis: poetry, 1925-1931; (TS) (Folder 27.221)
    - Barbara Burnett Gratwick: travel notes/ diaries: Russia, 1930; (MS diary) (Folder 27.222)
    - Grace Lynn: Arteff Theatre article, undated; (TS) (Folder 27.223)
    - Henry N. MacCracken: commencement address [re: Federal Theatre Project], 1939; (TS carbon, 2 copies) (Folder 27.224)
    - Herbert A. Price: "WPA Players Brighten the Lot of Refugees,", 1937; (TS carbon) (Folder 27.225)
    - Hilda W. Smith: "A Summary of Workers' Education Under the WPA,", 1938; (mimeograph) (Folder 27.226)
    - Molly Day Thacher: Blocks, [1928?]; (TS carbon) (Folder 27.227)
    - Iris Vinton: "Filling the Seats: a Report on Audience Building,", [1929]; (TS carbon) (Folder 27.228)
    - Hal Welles: Excerpt from novel [character based on HFD], undated; (photocopy of TS) (Folder 27.229)
    - [s.n.]: "Analysis of Federal Theatre Plays Critized [sic] on the Floors of the U.S. Senate and House,", [1939?]; (TS) (Folder 27.230)
    - [unknown Congressman]: Report on investigation of Federal Theatre Project, 1939; (TS carbon) (Folder 27.231)
    - [s.n.]: Essay re: Federal Theatre Project in New York City, 1939; (TS) (Folder 27.232)
- SERIES III. PRINTED MATERIALS and CLIPPINGS, circa 1909-1988
  - Materials about HFD and her publications
    - Clippings, circa 1909, 1925-1935; (29 items) (Folder 28.233)
    - Clippings, 1936-1942; (43 items) (Folder 28.234)
    - Clippings, [1943-1988]; (35 items) (Folder 28.235)
    - Book reviews, undated; (29 items) (Folder 28.236)
    - Awards and honors, undated; (6 items) (Folder 28.237)
    - Bookplate, undated; (1 item) (Folder 28.238)
  - Federal Theatre Project: General
    - Flyers and programs, 1937; (7 items) (Folder 28.239)
    - Clippings and articles, 1937; (41 items) (Folder 28.240)
    - Publications: "First Federal Summer Theatre -- A Report,", 1937; (2 copies) (Folder 28.241)
    - Programs, 1936-1939; (10 items) (Folder 28.242)
    - Clippings and articles, 1936-1937; (23 items) (Folder 28.243)
    - Clippings and articles, 1938-1941; (26 items) (Folder 28.244)
    - Clippings and articles, 1961-1974, undated; (14 items) (Folder 29.245)
    - Clipping: "Hallie Flanagan, Director of WPA Theatre Sends Open Letter to Congressman Woodrum," Sunday Worker, 1939 Jun 18 (Map Case - Drawer 44)
    - Clipping: "Thousands Sign Petitions to Save W.P.A. Theatre Projects," Sunday Worker, 1938 Jun 18 (Map Case - Drawer 44)
    - Clipping: "One-third of a Nation: a Handbook of Source Materials,", 1984; (1 item) (Folder 29.246)
    - Congressional Record, 1936 Apr 20 - May 7 (Folder 29.247)
    - Congressional Record, 1936 Jun 17 (Folder 29.248)
    - Congressional Record, 1939 Jan 23 - Apr 7 (Folder 29.249)
    - Congressional Record, 1936 Jun 15 (Folder 29.250)
    - Congressional Record, 1939 Jun 28 (Folder 29.251)
  - Federal Theatre Project: Publications - Play Bureau Lists
    - Russian Plays, 1936 Apr (Folder 30.252)
    - A Suggested Production List of Non-Royalty plays -- Part I and Part II, 1936 Oct (Folder 30.253)
    - 90 New Plays, 1936 Dec (Folder 30.254)
    - 91 New Plays, 1936 Dec; (copy 2) (Folder 30.255)
    - 34 Old and New Spanish Plays, 1937 Jan (Folder 31.256)
    - Jewish Non-royalty Plays and Pageants, 1937 Jan (Folder 31.257)
    - Rural Plays -- Part I, 1937 Mar (Folder 31.258)
    - Rural Plays -- Part II, 1937 Apr (Folder 31.259)
    - Patriotic Holiday Plays -- Non-royalty, Part II, 1937 Apr (Folder 31.260)
    - Rural Plays -- Part I, 1937 Jun; (3 copies) (Folder 32.261)
    - Rural Plays -- Part III, 1937 Jun; (3 copies) (Folder 32.262)
    - Some New Unpublished One-act Plays -- Royalty Plays, Part I, 1937 Jul; (2 copies) (Folder 32.263)
    - 72 Vaudeville Sketches -- Non-royalty, Part I, 1937 Sep (Folder 32.264)
  - Federal Theatre Project: Publications - Service Bureau Lists
    - Anti-war Plays -- Foreign and Jewish Lists, 1937 Oct (Folder 33.265)
    - Anti-war Plays -- Royalty List, 1937 Nov (Folder 33.266)
    - Anti-war Plays for Community Theatres, 1937 Oct (Folder 33.267)
    - Anti-war Plays for Community Theatres, 1937 Oct (Folder 33.268)
    - 40 Vaudeville Sketches -- Royalty, Part 2, 1937 Nov (Folder 33.269)
    - 57 Vaudeville Sketches, 1938 Jan; (reissued) (Folder 34.270)
    - Anglo-Jewish Plays in English and Yiddish, 1938 Jan (Folder 34.271)
    - Catholic Plays -- Parts II and III, 1938 Feb (Folder 34.272)
    - 56 Minstrels, 1938 Feb (Folder 34.273)
    - National Service Bureau Publications -- A Catalogue, 1938 Mar (Folder 35.274)
    - A List of Negro Plays, 1938 Mar (Folder 35.275)
    - 72 Vaudeville Sketches -- Non-royalty, Part II, 1938 Mar (Folder 35.276)
    - Old Testament Plays, 1938 Jul (Folder 35.277)
    - 59 Monologues, 1938 Dec (Folder 35.278)
    - New Plays Survey, 1938 Dec (Folder 35.279)
  - Federal Theatre Project: Publications - Play Bureau Play scripts
    - Class of 1929: A Play in Three Acts, 1936 (Folder 36.280)
    - Battle Hymn -- A Play in Three Acts, 1936 Oct (Folder 36.281)
    - John Henry -- Steel Driving Man, [1936?] (Folder 36.282)
    - Threnody American -- A Radio Drama About Youth, 1937 Jun; (2 copies) (Folder 37.283)
    - Late Primitive -- A Marionette Play in Two Acts, 1937 Jul (Folder 37.284)
    - The Wildcats -- A Play About Youth, 1937 Jul; (2 copies) (Folder 37.285)
    - The Lost Generation -- A Play About Youth, 1937 Jul; (2 copies) (Folder 37.286)
    - We Are the Future -- A Play of Rural Youth, 1937 Jul; (2 copies) (Folder 38.287)
    - Morning Paper -- A Play About Newsboys, 1937 Jul (Folder 38.288)
    - Sherlock Holmes -- Adapted for Marionettes, 1937 Jul (Folder 38.289)
    - Don Quixote -- Adapted for the Marionette Theater, 1937 Jul (Folder 38.290)
    - Nelagony, 1937 Nov (Folder 38.291)
    - Folk Tunes from Mississippi, 1937 Dec; (2nd edition) (Folder 38.292)
  - Dies Committee
    - Excerpts from hearings [Federal Theatre Project chapter from Thirty Years of Treason], 1938; (photocopies) (Folder 41.305)
    - Vassar student reactions [from Vassar Review, New York Times, Miscellany News], 1939; (photocopies) (Folder 41.306)
  - Grinnell College
    - Early Grinnell, Iowa: Bartlett Family, undated; (photocopies) (Folder 41.307)
    - Early 20th century history, undated; (photocopies) (Folder 41.308)
    - Biographical information about Professors. Edward A. Steiner and John D. Stoops, undated; (photocopies) (Folder 41.309)
    - Publications: Grinnell College Bulletin, 1920-1926; (photocopies of excerpts) (Folder 41.310)
    - Department of Theater: programs and clippings, 1921-1925; (21 pages; photocopies) (Folder 41.311)
  - 47 Workshop
    - Programs, 1923-1924; (7 pages; photocopies) (Folder 41.312)
  - Pamona College
    - Clippings, 1925 Summer; (3 pages; photocopies) (Folder 41.313)
  - Vassar College
    - Vassar Experimental Theater, Vassar Drama Department: clippings/articles, 1917, 1928-1940, 1983, undated; (27 items; some photocopies) (Folder 41.314)
    - Vassar Experimental Theater: programs, 1928-1940; (13 items) (Folder 41.315)
    - Summer session in the theater: programs/flyers, 1935; (4 items) (Folder 41.316)
    - Summer session in the theater: clippings, 1935; (8 pages; photocopies) (Folder 41.317)
    - Dutchess County Players, 1938; (1 item) (Folder 41.318)
    - HFD Powerhouse Theater, 1973-1974; (4 items) (Folder 41.319)
  - Smith College
    - Department of Theater: clippings/articles, 1945-1950; (7 items) (Folder 41.320)
    - Department of Theater: programs, 1945-1950; (3 items) (Folder 41.321)
    - Department of Theater: Denton Snyder: clippings/articles, undated; (2 items) (Folder 41.322)
    - Historical sketch of Northampton, MA, from New York Times, 1980 Feb 10; (photocopy) (Folder 41.323)
  - Miscellaneous articles on theater and dance
    - American theater: misc. clippings/articles, 1925-1936, 1980; (5 items) (Folder 42.324)
    - American theater: New York theater reviews, [1929 Feb-Mar?]; (14 items; photocopies) (Folder 42.325)
    - Workers' theaters: New Masses clippings, 1930 Jan - 1931 Jun; (17 items) (Folder 42.326)
    - Workers' theaters: The International Worker's Theater, articles from no. 4, 1931 May; (17 items) (Folder 42.326)
    - Workers' theaters: programs and flyers, undated; (4 items) (Folder 42.327)
    - Russian Theater: clippings and scrapbook articles, 1925-1934; (12 items; photocopies) (Folder 42.328)
    - Russian Theater: programs/flyers, [1930?]; (1 item) (Folder 42.329)
    - English Theater: clippings/articles, 1934; (8 items; photocopies) (Folder 42.330)
    - English Theater: programs/flyers, [1934?]; (10 items) (Folder 42.331)
    - Italian Theater: clippings/articles, 1934; (6 items; photocopies) (Folder 42.332)
    - Italian Theater: programs/flyers, 1929-1934; (12 items) (Folder 42.333)
    - French Theater: clippings/articles, 1934; (1 item: photocopy, original) (Folder 42.334)
    - French Theater: programs/flyers, 1934; (2 items) (Folder 42.335)
    - Miscellaneous clippings during European trip, 1934; (5 items; photocopies) (Folder 42.336)
    - Dance: clippings/articles, 1928-1933; (19 items; some photocopies) (Folder 42.337)
    - Dance: New York dance productions: programs/flyers, [1930's?]; (7 items) (Folder 42.338)
    - Dance: miscellaneous illustrations, undated; (6 items) (Folder 42.339)
  - Clippings and articles about others
    - Rachel Crothers, undated (Folder 43.340)
    - T.S. Eliot, 1982 Nov 21 (Folder 43.340a)
    - L.K. Elmhirst obituary, 1974 (Folder 43.341)
    - Horsley Gantt, 1980-1987; (7 items) (Folder 43.342)
    - Eugene O'Neill, 1935; (1 item) (Folder 43.343)
  - Unused Postcards
    - Russian trip, 1930; (43 items) (Folder 43.344)
    - Russian trip, 1930; (23 items) (Folder 43.345)
    - Russian trip, 1930; (35 items) (Folder 43.346)
    - European trip: England, 1934; (2 items) (Folder 43.347)
    - European trip: Paris?, [1934?]; (4 items) (Folder 43.348)
  - Miscellaneous printed materials
    - No parasan = They shall not pass, 1937; (song) (Folder 43.349)
    - Theatre materials from Prague, 1927; (3 volumes) (Folder 43.349a)
    - Tvorcheskii Teatr by Kerzhentsev, 1923; (1 volume) (Folder 43.349b)
- SERIES IV. INSTITUTIONAL and ORGANIZATIONAL MATERIALS, 1923-1969
  - Harvard University/Radcliffe College
    - English 39: HF's notes and essays, 1923 Fall (Folder 44.350)
    - 47 Workshop: miscellaneous notes of HF's, 1923 (Folder 44.351)
  - Vassar College
    - Drama/English departmental reports and memos, 1926-1935 (Folder 44.352)
    - Drama course outlines/syllabi, 1927-1937 (Folder 44.353)
    - Drama course exam questions/ paper assignments, 1930-1935 (Folder 44.354)
    - Drama course student notes, 1939 (Folder 44.355)
    - Grade sheets for English 270, English 370, 1933; (RESTRICTED) (Folder 45.356)
    - English 270: Elizabeth Dix (VC 1936): scrapbook with class notes and theater clippings/programs, 1934-1935 (Folder 46.357)
    - [English 370?]: Elizabeth Dix (VC 1936): notebook on design theory in theater and arts in general, 1935-1936 (Folder 46.358)
    - English 105: Katherine Dain (VC 1940): "George Pierce Baker and the 47 Workshop,", 1936-1937 (Folder 46.359)
    - Margaret Levi (VC 1935): Scrapbook with theater clippings for the period and her commentary, 1934-1935 (Folder 47.360)
  - Smith College
    - Department of Theater meeting minutes and miscellaneous reports, [1948-1950] (Folder 48.362)
    - Miscellaneous course outlines, assignments, discussion outlines, exam questions, [1947-1951] (Folder 48.363)
    - Miscellaneous course notes/outlines: Doris Abramson?, [circa 1950] (Folder 48.364)
    - List of drama students, classes of 1943-1954, 1969 (Folder 48.365)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Federal Theater Project: meeting minutes and miscellaneous reports, [1935-1939]; (all but 8-9 October 1935 are photocopies) (Folder 48.361)
    - Iowa Summer Session: "Theater and Society" course outline, 1945 (Folder 48.366)
    - Dartington Hall: notes on the theater session, 1950 Summer (Folder 48.367)
- SERIES V. PRODUCTION SCRIPTS/MATERIALS, circa 1925-1953
  - Vassar Experimental Theatre
    - All College Revue, circa 1925 (Folder 49.368)
    - Man and the Masses, by Ernst Toller, 1930 Spring (Folder 49.369)
    - Drama of Lights, by Paolo Buzzi; Alteration of Character, by Arnaldo Corradini and Bruno Corra, 1931-1932; (Esther Porter's (VC 1932) copy) (Folder 49.370)
    - Not for Us Alone, [acting versions of Greek mimes], by Hallie Flanagan and Philip Davis, circa 1932 (Folder 49.371)
    - Production notes for Antony and Cleopatra, 1934 Dec (Folder 49.372)
    - Question Before the House, by Doris Yankauer (VC 1935) and Herb Mayer, (fragment) (Folder 49.373)
    - Come Out Into the Sun: Tentative rehearsal schedule, 1935 Aug (Folder 49.374)
    - Miscellaneous scripts [Greek drama], 1936-1937; (6 items) (Folder 49.375)
    - Plan for mime sequence, undated; (1 TS; 1 TS carbon) (Folder 49.376)
  - Federal Summer Theatre at Vassar
    - General information about program, undated (Folder 50.377)
    - Lists of personnel, undated (Folder 50.378)
    - Schedules, undated (Folder 50.379)
    - How Long Brethren (July 10): General information, undated (Folder 50.380)
    - One-third of the Nation (July 29-31): Ticket information, undated (Folder 50.381)
    - Lists of electrical equipment, undated (Folder 50.382)
    - Invoices, undated (Folder 50.383)
    - Transportation reimbursement forms, undated (Folder 50.384)
  - Federal Theatre Project, [193?]
    - [Federal Theatre Project?]: Secret Weapon, by Herbert Barr Lutz, undated; (TS) (Folder 51.385)
  - Smith College, [1944-1945
    - Yes Is for a Very Young Man, by Gertrude Stein, 1944-1945; (mimeograph of TS with notes by HFD) (Folder 51.386)
    - The Tragical History of Dr. Faustus, by Christopher Marlow, 1945 Fall; (mimeograph) (Folder 51.387)
    - Heritage - A Play in Honor of the 75th Anniversary of the Founding of Smith College, 1953 Jun (Folder 51.388)
- SERIES VI. SCRAPBOOK, 1907-1911
  - Scrapbook of Hallie Mae Ferguson at Grinnell College, 1907-1911 (Folder 52.389)
- SERIES VII. PHOTOGRAPHIC MATERIAL, circa 1890 - circa 1982
  - Professional
    - Grinnell College: Murray Flanagan, 1906; (1 photo) (Folder 53.390)
    - Grinnell College: Drama Department: "Romeo Juliet,", 1925; (2 photos) (Folder 53.391)
    - Vassar College: Drama Department: Lester and Philena Lang, undated; (3 photos) (Folder 53.392)
    - Vassar College: Drama Department: Nikander and Kay Strelsky, Eve and Harry St. John Williams, HFD, circa 1930; (2 copies) (Folder 53.393)
    - Russian Theatre, circa 1930; (45 photos) (Folder 53.394)
    - Travel photos: Russia, 1930; (12 photos) (Folder 53.395)
    - Travel photos: Europe, 1926 Dec; (1 photo; 1 postcard) (Folder 53.396)
    - Travel photos: Europe, 1934 May; (1 photo; 1 postcard) (Folder 53.397)
    - Federal Theatre Project: "Murder in the Cathedral,", 1936; (1 photo from magazine) (Folder 53.398)
    - Federal Theatre Project: "Triple-A Plowed Under,", 1936; (10 photos) (Folder 53.399)
    - Dance: Miscellaneous, undated; (5 photos) (Folder 53.400)
    - Smith College: Hallie Flanagan Davis, 1942-1949; (photocopies of 11 photographs from the Smith College Archives) (Folder 53.401)
    - Smith College: Exhibit in Hallie Flanagan Studio Theatre, circa 1982; (12 photos) (Folder 53.402)
    - Miscellaneous non-family individuals, undated; (2 photos: 1 sketch) (Folder 53.403)
  - Family
    - Hallie Flanagan Davis, [circa 1890-1894]; (31 photos) (Folder 54.404)
    - Hallie Flanagan Davis Grave site, 1969; (2 photos) (Folder 54.405)
    - [William J. Fischer?], [1906?]; (1 photo) (Folder 54.406)
    - Unidentified early), undated; (1 photo) (Folder 54.407)
    - Ferguson House Grinnell, 1952; (2 photos) (Folder 54.408)
    - Murray Flanagan with family, undated; (4 photos) (Folder 54.409)
    - Photograph album, [circa 1914-1921] (Folder 54.410)
    - Jack and Frederic Flanagan, undated; (8 photos) (Folder 54.411)
    - Philip Davis and children, [1929-1938]; (12 photos) (Folder 54.412)
- SERIES VIII. AUDIO RECORDINGS and TRANSCRIPTS, 1967-1985
  - Interviews by Joanne Bentley
    - Relatives - Kenneth Ferguson, 1979-1980; (TRS) (Folder 55.414)
    - Relatives - Jack Davis, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 55.415)
    - Classmates (high school) - George Clifton, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 55.416)
    - Students (Grinnell) - Bernard Craven, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 55.417)
    - Students (Grinnell) - Howard Wicks, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 55.418)
    - Students (Vassar) - Anne Oliver Bassage, VC 1935, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 55.419)
    - Students (Vassar) - Barbara Gratwick, VC 1928, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 55.420)
    - Students (Vassar) - Jerry Harvey Guthrie, VC 1924, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 55.421)
    - Students (Vassar) - Kay Hocking, VC 1929, 1979; (TRS) (Folder 55.422)
    - Students (Vassar) - Mary Crapo Hyde, VC 1934, [198?]; (TRS) (Folder 55.423)
    - Students (Vassar) - Esther Porter Lane, VC 1932, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 55.424)